Nithin Gangadharan

gangadharan.n@husky.neu.edu | +1 (857) 869-3415 | Boston, MA linkedin.com/in/gnithin | github.com/gnithin | stackoverflow.com/users/1518924 | gnithin.github.io

SUMMARY

Pursuing Masters in Computer Science at Northeastern University. Have been writing software professionally for 5 years. Have experience writing code for the web (vanilla JavaScript, and React), mobile frameworks (iOS - Objective-C), and backend services (Golang, JavaScript, Python, PHP) in different languages. Have worked with various SQL and NoSQL databases and have extensively used Google Cloud Platform(GCP) and Firebase ecosystems for deploying services.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Sept 2019 - Current

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering, University of Pune, Pune, India

Aug 2010 - May 2014

First Class with Distinction

SKILLS

Programming: Javascript, React, Go, Python, Objective-C
Databases/Cache: MySQL, MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Dgraph, Redis

IDE: VSCode, GoLand, Vim Message Queues: Kafka, Google Pub-Sub

Others: Git, Mac OS X

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Development Engineer, Media.Net, Pune, India

Aug 2018 - Jul 2019

- Designed and implemented a backend prediction service, which was part of a larger mobile crawler system, that helped predict future pages from existing crawled data
- Built multiple Single Page Applications(SPA) in **React** and hosted them on **Firebase**. Some of the sites were dashboards that helped monitor revenue for existing services in the company
- Mentored an intern for 3 months, on iOS and Javascript applications. Managed their day-to-day tasks and helped get their code into live projects

Software Developer, Media.Net, Pune, India

Dec 2016 - Aug 2018

- Built iOS ad-sdks in Objective-C dedicated ad-sdks that supported Banner, Interstitial and Video ads, and a Header-Bidding ad-sdk with Banner and Interstitial ad-slots
- Built an iOS mobile-crawler-sdk, that crawled the mobile apps it was injected into, and obtained data for delivering higher quality contextual advertisements
- Developed corresponding apis for the ad-sdks in Golang and Node. js, hosted in Google Cloud Functions, backed by Google Datastore
- Built a tool to automate testing of the iOS ad-sdk. The tool injects the ad-sdk into enterprise-signed iOS client applications.
 This tool debugged client issues and helped the team, at multiple instances, in discovering integration issues with new client applications, and always ensured backward compatibility in new releases

Software Engineer, Ignite Solutions, Pune, India

Apr 2015 - Dec 2016

- Joined a team of 9 engineers at a services startup, creating technical solutions for web and mobile applications
- Created RESTful apis for a social networking application, using PHP and Python in Google App Engine, with Google CloudSQL as the primary database
- Maintained an iOS application written in Objective-C, fixed major implementation issues and improved performance
- Built multiple responsive websites, using Bootstrap and JQuery

Associate Software Engineer, ACI Worldwide, Pune, India

Jul 2014 - Mar 2015

- Built payment adapters (endpoints between two payment systems) using a Java based tool
- Contributed in the development of the tool and helped build initial prototype solutions
- Found and fixed multiple bugs affecting the day-to-day functioning of adapters